roalddahl.com 2019-07-19

# Privacy Policy - RoaldDahl.com

**BY USING OUR SITE OR OTHERWISE COMMUNICATING WITH US YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

For information on how we work with children 12 and under in the United States and 15 and under in the EU please see our [Children's Privacy Policy](http://www.roalddahl.com/global/childrens-privacy-policy)

**Kids Privacy Assured by PRIVO: COPPA Safe Harbor Certification & GDPR _kids_ ™**

The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd is a member of the PRIVO Kids Privacy Assured Program (“the Program”) for COPPA Safe Harbor Certification and GDPR _kids_ ™. PRIVO is an independent, third-party organization committed to safeguarding children's personal information collected online.

**COPPA Safe Harbor Certification**

The Program certification applies to the digital properties listed on the validation page that is viewable by clicking on the PRIVO COPPA certification seal. The certification seal posted on this page indicates The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd has established COPPA compliant privacy practices and has agreed to submit to PRIVO’s oversight and consumer dispute resolution process. If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact us at +44 (0)20 3696 6450 or contact@roalddahl.com. If you have further concerns after you have contacted us, you can contact PRIVO directly at privacy@privo.com.

**GDPR _kids_ ™ Privacy Assured**

The Program applies to the digital properties listed on the validation page that is viewable by clicking on the PRIVO GDPR _kids_ ™ Verified Shield. The PRIVO GDPR _kids_ ™ Privacy Assured Program supports child directed services known as Information Society Services under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), to comply with the requirements of this legislation. It impacts any child directed service in an EU Member State and any service globally that collects and or processes the personal data of children and minors. There is no safe harbor for the GDPR to date, but to ensure this company's services meet the program requirements, we conduct regular monitoring and consulting.

This Privacy Policy (together with our  _Terms of Use_ ,  _Acceptable Use Policy_  and  _Cookie Policy_  and any other document referred to in it) describes the way we collect your personal information (whether collected from you or otherwise provided to us), how we use your personal information and why.

Please read the following information carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it.

Your right to privacy is important to us. We take the security of your personal information seriously and we have strict policies and processes in place to ensure it remains safe.

**CONTENTS**

  1. **Definitions**
  2. **Information we may collect from you**
  3. **Information third parties may collect from you**
  4. **How we use your information**
  5. **Who we share your information with and why**
  6. **Where we store your information**
  7. **Your rights**
  8. **Updates to this policy**
  9. **How to contact us about your privacy**
  10. **Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd. Recruitment Privacy Notice**
  11. **Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre Recruitment Privacy Notice**
  12. **Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity Recruitment Privacy Notice**

In this Privacy Policy," **we** ", " **us** " and " **our** " means The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd. We are a limited company incorporated in England and Wales with company no OC393071 and our registered address is 5 New Street Square, London, EC4A 3TW, United Kingdom. If you provide us with personal information via or through using our website, www.roalddahl.com ("our site") or by otherwise communicating with us, we will process your personal information in accordance with all applicable data protection laws, including the EU General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) (GDPR).

Our site brings together the work of various entities committed to protecting and furthering the works of Roald Dahl and his legacy. For example, our site allows you to:

  * purchase books written by Roald Dahl and various other Roald Dahl related memorabilia;
  * purchase tickets for entry to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre;
  * make donations to Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity;
  * find out more about the work of the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre and Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity and the social benefit they each bring, as well as each of their various fundraising appeals and events;
  * to subscribe for email newsletters so you can keep up to date with personal information and the latest news about Roald Dahl, the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre and Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity.

So that we can do all of this and more, we will need to share your information with Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity (company no 07340518, registered charity number 1137409) (" **Marvellous** "); The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre (company no 04178505, registered charity number 1085853) (" **Museum** "); The Roald Dahl Centre (Trading) Limited (company no 04854808) (" **Trading** "); (together the " **Roald Dahl Group** ") and other independent third party businesses, as we have explained below in more detail.

Where your requests or instructions are specifically related to another Roald Dahl Group company both us and that company will each act as a controller in respect of that data and we will each process your personal data in accordance with (a) this policy (and the words "we", "us", and "our" shall where the context requires, also refer to any other Roald Dahl Group company that controls such data) and (b) any other policy that the other Roald Dahl Group company may provide to you.

Where your information is processed by a third party company it will only be processed on our documented instructions or where information is processed by a third party on behalf of one of the other Roald Dahl Group companies on the documented instructions of the Roald Dahl Group Company (acting as controller).

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**

**We may collect and process the following information about you:**

  * **Information you give us.**  You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our site or by corresponding with us by telephone, e-mail or otherwise howsoever. This includes information you provide when you: use our site; register to use our site; subscribe to receive newsletters and marketing (via email) about Roald Dahl, the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity (including details about products, activities and events, details of discounts, voucher codes and offers and campaigns, competitions and other opportunities from any of the Roald Dahl Group); search for products on our site; place an order for products on our site; place an order for tickets to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre via our site; make a donation to Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity; participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on our site (such as making Contributions (as the term is defined in our Acceptable Use Policy); enter a competition, promotion or survey; apply for a grant from Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity; and/or when you contact us to report a problem with our site. The information you give us may include your title, first and last names, address, country of residence, e-mail address and contact telephone number, date of birth, your user type (e.g. parent/guardian, teacher, child or other type of user), personal messages you wish to send to recipients of products that you have ordered from Trading via our site and/or details relating to why you are corresponding/contacting us. Depending on whether or not you decide to purchase products from Trading, you may also give us financial and credit card information.
  * **Information we collect about you.**  Records of our contact with you, which may include notes on our systems, emails or electronic communications and written correspondence and any telephone number used by you to call our customer service phone number.

With regard to each of your visits to our site we may automatically collect the following information:

  * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type (e.g. Safari or Internet Explorer) and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform;
  * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time); products, pages and items you viewed, searched for or purchased; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

To the extent that any of this information constitutes personal data under applicable data protection laws, including the GDPR, we will process this in accordance with such laws.

**Information we receive from other sources.  **Information we receive from other sources. We work closely with third parties (including, for example, delivery fulfilment providers and courier service providers, business partners, technical and payment services providers, advertising networks, analytics providers and search information providers) to ensure that our site and the information and/or services we provide to you work effectively and we may receive information about you from them. This will include information that we receive from:

  * Gardners Books Limited (company no 02010127) ("Gardners") (our delivery fulfilment provider) who will confirm to us if and when they have despatched to you products that you have ordered via our site from Trading. This is so that we can monitor the efficiency of our online shop and the efficiency of our delivery fulfilment provider; and
  * Rocket Science Group LLC (trading as 'Mailchimp') who will provide us with information about whether or not you have received and read email newsletters and email marketing that they send on our behalf (and only with your informed and express consent) to you. This is so that we can monitor the reception of those email newsletters and email marketing.
  * SurveyMonkey Inc (trading as Wufoo), who will provide us with online form building services for communication with us through our website
  * Formstack LLC, who provide customer engagement services.
  * Mailgun Technologies Inc. who provide customer engagement and mailing services.
  * DJS Research Ltd, who provide survey and reseach services to Museum by collecting any feedback that you provide about the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre when you click through to their survey from our site.

**INFORMATION THIRD PARTIES MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**

  * **Cookies.**  Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This includes third party cookies. These third party cookies help us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site, to provide you with content that is most relevant to you (e.g. when you have told us whether you are a parent/guardian, teacher, child or other type of user), to process and analyse your navigation and use of our site, to understand your interests and demographic and to target certain marketing and to allow us to improve our site. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, please read our Cookie Policy
  * **Purchasing products from Trading via our site.**  If you use our site to purchase products from Trading via the online shop on our site, we use a third party, Gardners Books Limited, to fulfil delivery of your order (see above "information we receive from other sources"). Gardners will collect information about you (i.e. your name, address, invoice address, delivery address, details of the products you have ordered from Trading via our site and any personal messages you wish to send to recipients of products you have ordered from Trading via our site) in order to deliver the products your order from Trading via our online store. Gardners will also collect information about the despatch of products to you (i.e. the address that the products were sent to and the date and time the products were despatched to that address);
  * **Subscribing to email newsletters and email marketing.**  If you ask us to keep you up to date, or permit selected third parties to keep you up to date (see "Who we share your information with" below), via email with the latest news and information about Roald Dahl, The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre and/or Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity, including the products that we and other entities in the Roald Dahl Group offer and events we and they are running, the various activities of the entities within the Roald Dahl Group, details of product discounts and other products available from our online store that may be of interest to you, details of fundraising activities, voucher codes and offers, campaigns, competitions and other opportunities to support our work and the work of the Roald Dahl Group, then Rocket Science Group LLC (trading as 'Mailchimp') will gather information to measure and understand and to permit entities in the Roald Dahl Group to measure and understand the effectiveness of the email communications sent to you. We also use Formsatck LLC (trading as 'Formstack') and Mailgun Technologies Inc (trading as "Mailgun") to assist with our customer engagement programmes to help us develop our communications that will enable you to understand how we use your data;
  * **Purchasing tickets to The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre.**  If you use our site to purchase tickets for admission to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, you will be re-directed to tickets.com (a website owned and operated by Tickets.com, Inc). All ticket purchase transactions for admission to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre are processed via the tickets.com website and, in the process of purchasing tickets via tickets.com, you will disclose personal information to Tickets.com, Inc. Any personal information you provide via the tickets.com website will be stored and processed in accordance with the privacy policy shown on the tickets.com website. Please read the privacy policy on the tickets.com website carefully. You acknowledge and agree that we are not, and none of the Roald Dahl Group are, responsible for the collection, use, processing, transfer and storage of any personal information you provide to the tickets.com website, nor the acts and/or omissions of tickets.com in respect of the collection, use, processing, transfer and storage of any personal information you provide to the tickets.com website. In order to process your ticket purchase and so that the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre can issue with your ticket, tickets.com will provide the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre with details of your ticket purchase (e.g. the number and type of tickets you have purchased and the date and time for when you have purchased those tickets). This so that Trading and the Museum know what tickets you have ordered and paid for when you arrive for your visit to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre. The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre will store and process some of that information (i.e. your name, address, phone number and email address) in order to facilitate any future bookings you may make for tickets to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre. If you choose to give feedback about the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre by clicking the relevant link on the site, you will be re-directed to a survey on a website operated by DJS Research Ltd, and DJS Research Ltd may share that feedback data with Museum.
  * **Making Donations.**  If you use our site to make a donation to Marvellous, you will, when you make one off donations to Marvellous, be re-directed to edirectdebits.com (a website owned and operated by Rapidata Services Plc) or thepayrollgivingteam.co.uk (a website owned and operated by The Payroll Giving Team Ltd) when you set up payroll giving donations to Marvellous, or roalddahl.charitycheckout.co.uk, a website owned and operated by Onling Giving Ltd. (T/A charity checkout) who handle the processing of our online payments. All donations to Marvellous made via our site are processed by Rapidata Services Plc, The Payroll Giving Team Ltd or Online Giving Ltd and, in the process of making a donation via any of the sites listed above, you will disclose personal information to the entities who own and operate those sites. Any personal information you provide to, Rapidata Services Plc, The Payroll Giving Team Ltd and/or Online Giving Ltd will be stored and processed in accordance with the privacy policy shown on edirectdebits.com, thepayrollgivingteam.co.uk or charitycheckout.co.uk. Please read the privacy policies on those websites carefully. You acknowledge and agree that we are not, and none of the Roald Dahl Group are, responsible for the collection, use, processing, transfer and storage of any personal information you provide to, Rapidata Services Plc, The Payroll Giving Team Ltd and/or Online Giving Ltd, nor the acts and/or omissions of Rapidata Services Plc, The Payroll Giving Team Ltd and/or Online Giving Ltd in respect of the collection, use, processing, transfer and storage of any personal information you provide to Rapidata Services Plc, The Payroll Giving Team Ltd and/or Online Giving Ltd. Please note that Rapidata Services PLC,The Payroll Giving Team Ltd and Online Giving Limited will provide Marvellous with some or all of the information they collect from you in respect of your donation. Please note that this may include your financial and credit card information.

**HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

**Information you give to us.**  We will use this information as follows:

  * to permit you to purchase products via our site and (for such purpose) to enter into contracts with another member of the Roald Dahl Group, namely Trading, for the purchase of those products
  * to include your email address, first name, last name, your alias (if any), country of residence and date of birth in a database (collated using a third party database aggregator, namely Rocket Science Group LLC (trading as 'Mailchimp') and Mailgun Technologies Inc (trading as 'Mailgun')). Mailchimp and Mailgun will have access to and will store and process this information, but will only do so on our instructions, so that we may contact you as described in the following bullet point. The function of the database aggregators is to help the Roald Dahl Group with conducting our newsletters and marketing campaigns and sending them to you via email. Using a database aggregator also allows the Roald Dahl Group to track the reception and take up of that newsletter and/or marketing campaign by those that subscribe to receive them. If you have not ticked the relevant box on our site indicating that you would like to receive such email newsletters and marketing campaigns, we will not disclose your personal information to Mailchimp or if we do need to obtain parental consent we will not share your personal information with Mailgun. Please see below at "Who we share your information with" and "Where we store your personal information", which sets our further details of the disclosure to Mailchimp and Mailgun of your personal information;
  * to keep you up to date, or permit selected third parties to keep you up to date (see "Who we share your information with" below), with the latest news and information about Roald Dahl, The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre and/or Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity, including the products that we and other entities in the Roald Dahl Group offer and events we and they are running, the various activities of the entities within the Roald Dahl Group, details of product discounts and other products available from our online store that may be of interest to you, details of fundraising activities, voucher codes and offers, campaigns, competitions and other opportunities to support our work and the work of the Roald Dahl Group. This will only happen where you have consented to receiving such news and information (e.g. by ticking the appropriate box on our site) from us and/or from the other entities within the Roald Dahl Group. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, or you do not want us to pass your details on to selected third parties for the purposes outlined above, please do not tick the relevant box on our site and, if you have ticked the relevant box in the past, please contact us at The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd, 5 Berkeley Mews, London, W1H 7PB, United Kingdom or [contact@roalddahl.com ](mailto:contact@roalddahl.com)and ask us to cease using your information in this way; or if you have previously ticked the box in relation to the Marvellous Children's Charity please contact us at the Marvellous Children's Charity, 23 Woodside Road, Amersham, Buckinghamshire HP6 6AA, United Kingdom or enquiries@roalddahlcharity.org and ask us to cease using your information in this way, or if you have previously ticked the box in relation to either The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, or the online shop on our site, please contact us at The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, 81-83 High Street, Great Missenden, Buckinghamshire, HP16 0AL or hello@roalddahlmuseum.org;
  * to allow you to participate in the interactive features of this site, when you choose to do so (for example, to post your Contributions to pages of our site);
  * to notify you about changes to our site, changes to the products and/or services offered via our site and/or changes to the terms and conditions and/or policies shown on our site; and/or
  * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * to contact you via email to invite you to comment on the services you may have received from us, as part of our ongoing website improvement and development. The services we may contact you about include the purchase of products from the Roald Dahl online store, incomplete purchases of products from the Roald Dahl online store, making a donation to Roald Dahl’s Marvellous Children’s Charity and buying tickets to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre.

**Information we collect about you.**  We and the entities of the Roald Dahl Group will use this information:

  * for the purposes of carrying out your requests (for example, to address matters relating to our site and/or the services provided via our site) which you make known to us in electronic communications, written correspondence and/or during telephone calls you make to our customer service number and for the purposes of keeping records of the aforementioned electronic communications, written correspondence and/or telephone calls;
  * to administer our site and for internal operations and to permit entities in the Roald Dahl Group to carry out internal operations (see "Who we share your personal information with" below). Such internal operations will involve troubleshooting of technical issues that arise in relation to our site; testing of our site following resolution of such technical issues; analysis of statistics arising from the information collected about you (for example, using information gathered by cookies on our site to ascertain what content on our site is accessed by members of a particular age group) and will only involve the use and/or processing of information in an anonymous form to measure and understand the effectiveness of the services provided via our site (for example, we may share aggregate information about the number of people who access our site and go on to purchase products via our site);
  * to improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our site, when you choose to do so;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about products or services that may interest you or them.
  * Information we receive from other sources. For information on how we will use information we receive from other sources, please see the explanation above at "Information third parties may collect from you".

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention schedule which you can request from us by emailing us at contact@roalddahl.com.

**WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH**

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may share your information with selected third parties:

  * **The Roald Dahl Centre (Trading) Limited, a member of the Roald Dahl Group.**  If you purchase products from our site, you will enter into a contract with The Roald Dahl Centre (Trading) Limited (see our Terms and Conditions of Sale of Goods. We will share the details of your order (i.e. your name, invoice address, delivery address, products you have ordered from Trading via our site, email address, contact telephone number, details of your payment and any personal messages you wish to send to recipients of products you have ordered from Trading via our site) with The Roald Dahl Centre (Trading) Limited so that they can take payment from you for the products you order from the online shop on our site and so that they can arrange for the delivery of such products to the address you specify in your order. Trading may also contact you to provide you with information about other products and services offered via the online store on our site that are similar to those that you have already purchased. Additionally, and only when you have expressly indicated (e.g. by ticking the relevant box on our site) that you wish to be kept up to date (via email) with the latest information and news about Roald Dahl, the products available from our online shop, details of discounts, voucher codes and offers, and competitions run by The Roald Dahl Centre (Trading) Limited, we will share your name, email address, country of residence, and date of birth with The Roald Dahl Centre (Trading) Limited so that they can fulfil your wish to be contacted about those matters and to ensure that the emails sent to you are appropriate to your age group and/or country of residence (e.g. Trading would not send an email to you advertising products that are available via our online store if you are under 16 years old; or in the USA, and under 13 years old). We will also share with Trading details of information gathered through cookies on our site (which may include details of your age, your gender, your country of residence and your language, but we will not be able to identify you from this data) to enable it to help us administer our site and for internal operations (i.e. troubleshooting of technical issues that arise in relation to our site; testing of our site following resolution of such technical issues; analysis of statistics arising from the information collected about you (for example, to analyse the geographical location and age profile of individuals who purchase products from the online store on our site));
  * **Gardners Books Limited,**  our delivery fulfilment provider. When you submit an order for products via our site, we will share with Gardners Books Limited your name, the invoice address, details of the products you have ordered from Trading via our site, the delivery address you set out in your order and any personal messages you wish to send to recipients of products you have ordered from Trading via our site. This is so that Gardner's Books Limited can fulfil your order for products;
  * **The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, a member of the Roald Dahl Group.**  We will share with The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre details of information gathered through cookies on our site (which may include details of your age, your gender, your country of residence and your language, but we will not be able to identify you from this data) to enable it to help us administer our site and for internal operations (i.e. troubleshooting of technical issues that arise in relation to our site; testing of our site following resolution of such technical issues; analysis of statistics arising from the information collected about you (for example, to ascertain where visitors to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre have travelled from and their age profile)) and so that the Museum can measure and understand the effectiveness of email newsletters and email marketing that are sent to you. Additionally and only where you have expressly indicated (e.g. by ticking the relevant box on our site) that you wish to be kept up to date (via email) with the latest information and news about Roald Dahl, events and activities at The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre, details of discounts, voucher codes and offers, details of fundraising opportunities, campaigns and competitions, we will share your name, email address, country of residence and date of birth with The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre so that it can fulfil your wish to be contacted about those matters and to ensure that the emails sent to you are appropriate to your age group and/or your country of residence (e.g. the Museum would not send an email to you about an event being held at the Museum if you tell us that your country of residence is New Zealand).
  * **Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity, a member of the Roald Dahl Group.**  We will share with Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity details of information gathered through cookies on our site (which may include details of your age, your gender, your country of residence and your language, but we will not be able to identify you from this data) to enable it to help us administer our site and for internal operations (i.e. troubleshooting of technical issues that arise in relation to our site; testing of our site following resolution of such technical issues; analysis of statistics arising from the information collected about you), and so that the Charity can measure and understand the effectiveness of email newsletters and email marketing that are sent to you. Additionally, and only where you have expressly indicated (e.g. by ticking the relevant box on our site) that you wish to be kept up to date (via email) with the latest information and news about Roald Dahl, fundraising opportunities, events, campaigns and competitions, and information about the work of the Charity, we will share your name, email address, country of residence and date of birth with Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity so that it can fulfil your wish to be contacted about those matters and to ensure that the emails sent to you are appropriate to your age group and/or country of residence (e.g. the Charity would not knowingly send an email to you asking you to make donations to Roald Dahl's Marvellous Children's Charity if you are under 16 years old; or in the USA and under 13 years old);
  * **Rocket Science Group LLC (trading as 'Mailchimp')** , our database aggregator. Where (and only where) you have expressly indicated (e.g. by ticking the relevant box on our site) that you wish to be sent email newsletters, email marketing materials and other information (via email), we will share with Mailchimp your email address, first name, last name, alias (if any), country of residence and date of birth to create a database of individuals who have subscribed for these services. We will use this database as we have described above (see "How we use your information");
  * **SurveyMonkey Inc (trading as Wufoo)** , who will provide us with online form building services for communication with us through our website
  * We may also share your information with trusted third parties for the purposes of market analysis and research. We will not disclose this information in a form which would allow you to be identified (for example, we may provide them with aggregate information about the number of copies of the book  _Charlie and The Chocolate Factory_  that have been sold via our site to residents of a particular post code);
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site; and/or
  * To disclose your identity to any third party who is claiming that any content posted or uploaded by you to our site constitutes a violation of their legal rights, including their intellectual property rights or of their right to privacy.

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * If The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal information held by it about its customers and website users will be one of the transferred assets;
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation; and/or
  * In order to enforce or apply our Terms of Website Use, our Terms and Conditions of Sale of Goods or our Terms and Conditions of Sale of Tickets; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd, any entity of the Roald Dahl Group, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Information you provide to us by corresponding with us by telephone, email or otherwise howsoever and which we collect will be filed and sorted at 5 Berkeley Mews, London, W1H 7PB (i.e. our trading address)or, for any information collected by Museum or Trading at 81-83 High Street, Great Missenden, Buckinghamshire, HP16 0AL (the trading address of Museum and Trading. Subject to the paragraph immediately below, the information you provide to us and which we collect is stored on secure servers of our website hosting services provider. This information will be stored at a destination within the European Economic Area ("EEA"). Staff members operating within the EEA who work for or on behalf of us and/or any of the entities in the Roald Dahl Group may process the information that you give to us and which we collect. Such staff members may, among other things, be involved in the provision of support services in relation to our site. When submitting your personal information, you are agreeing to such processing, transfer or storage as outlined in this Privacy Policy. We will ensure at all times to take all reasonable steps necessary to maintain the security of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

The information that we collect from you and disclose to Rocket Science LLC (trading as 'Mailchimp') (see "Who we share your information with" above), will be transferred and may be stored at a destination outside the EEA (including the USA, where the level of protection given to your personal data may be less than is legally required in the EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA (including in the USA, where the level of protection given to your personal data may be less than is legally required in the EEA) who work for Mailchimp. Mailchimp will access, use and store such information in accordance with the Mailchimp Privacy Policy ([http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy//](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)). Mailchimp have agreed that they will only process your personal information in accordance with our documented instructions. However, please note that Mailchimp are an independent company and we do not control Mailchimp. If you do not feel comfortable with any of this, then please do not subscribe via our site to receive newsletters or marketing via email (i.e. do not complete the relevant form on our site).

Payment transactions for the purchase of products (other than tickets to the Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre) from our site are processed using SagePay, a  secure online gateway that encrypts your card details and cannot be accessed by us.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure.

Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to access the personal information we hold about you. This is called a Subject Access Request. Should you wish to make a Subject Access Request, please make your Subject Access Request to us in writing to The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd, 5 Berkeley Mews, London, W1H 7PB, United Kingdom or email to [contact@roalddahl.com](mailto:contact@roalddahl.com).Or if you wish to make a Subject Access Request to the Marvellous Childrens Charity, please write to Marvellous at 23 Woodside Road, Amersham, Buckinghamshire, HP66AA,UnitedKingdom or enquiries@roalddahlcharity.org. Orifyouwishtomake a Subject Access Request to either Museum or Trading please write to us at 81-83 High Street, Great Missenden, Buckinghamshire, HP16 0AL or email us at hello@roalddahlmuseum.org.

If we no longer have a legal basis to process your personal data or if the legal basis that we are relying on is consent and you subsequently withdraw your consent then we will stop processing your personal data. If you inform us that you no longer wish to be contacted by us we will need to maintain a record of that to make sure that we do not contact you again in the future.

You have the right to contact us to correct any inaccuracies in your personal data. Under certain circumstances you may have the right to instruct us to erase your personal data or provide the data to another person or organisation.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. We will inform you (before collecting your personal information) if we intend to use your personal information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your personal information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by not ticking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your personal information on our site and/or by changing your cookie settings on your internet browser (see our Cookie Policy for further information on how to do this). You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd, 5 Berkeley Mews, London, W1H 7PB or [contact@roalddahl.com](mailto:contact@roalddahl.com).

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers, affiliates and other independent third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and terms of use and that we do not and none of the Roald Dahl Group accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or terms. Please check these policies and terms before you submit any personal information to these websites.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

This policy is effective from March 2014. We may need to change our Privacy Policy from time to time to keep it up to date. Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy was last updated 1 August 2018

**CONTACT**

If you have any questions about the way in which we collect or process your information, please contact us. You can also find out more about your rights under applicable data protection laws, including the GDPR, by visiting the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) website at [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/) or by writing to: Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, SK9 5AF. If you believe that your rights have not been respected at any time then you also have a right to contact the ICO to ask them for a resolution.

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd, 5 Berkeley Mews, London, W1H 7PB, United Kingdom or emailed to [contact@roalddahl.com.](mailto:contact@roalddahl.com)

**THE ROALD DAHL STORY COMPANY LTD – RECRUITMENT PRIVACY NOTICE**

**What will we do with your information?**

The information that applicants provide during the recruitment and selection process will only be used for the purpose of progressing their application, or to fulfil legal or regulatory requirements if necessary. The information provided will be held securely by us in an electronic and/or physical format.

THE ROALD DAHL STORY COMPANY LTD will not share any of the information provided during the recruitment process with any third parties for marketing purposes or store any of your information outside of the United Kingdom or the European Union.

We will use the contact details provided to us to contact applicants in order to progress their application. We will use the other information provided to assess their suitability for the role that they have applied for. 

**What information do we ask for, and why?**

The information that we ask for (whether from the applicant or from the applicant’s referees) is used to assess the applicant’s suitability for employment and progress their application. We do not collect more information than we need to fulfil our stated purposes and will retain it for the period of time set out below.

Applicants don’t have to provide what we ask for - however it may affect their application if they don’t.

**Application Stage**

At the application stage we ask applicants for the following details:

  * Their name
  * Their address
  * Their phone number
  * Their email address
  * Details of their previous experience, including education, work history, referees and answers to questions in relation to the role that they have applied for

We may request for the above details to be provided to us in the form of a CV, cover letter, examples of their work and/or a portfolio. Our HR team and applicable recruiting team members will have access to all of this information.

Applicants may be asked to provide equal opportunities information. This information is not mandatory and if applicants choose not to provide it, it will not affect their application. This information will not be made available to any staff outside of our HR team in a way which can identify the applicant. Any information that is provided will be used only to produce and monitor equal opportunities statistics. 

**Selection Stage**

Our applicable recruiting team members shortlist applications for interview in conjunction with the HR team.

We may ask the applicant to take part in a telephone screening call, attend an interview and/or complete tests – or a combination of these. Information will be generated by the applicant and by us. As an example, the applicant might complete a written test, or we might take interview notes. This information is held by us.

**How long is the information retained for?**

If an applicant is unsuccessful at any stage of the process, the information provided until that point will be retained for 6 months.

Information from successful applicants will be retained in accordance with our internal Personnel Information and Data Protection policy.

Any queries about how THE ROALD DAHL STORY COMPANY LTD handles applicant information should be made to:

GDPR Owner

The Roald Dahl Story Company Ltd

5 Berkeley Mews

London

W1H 7PB

Applicants who have any concerns regarding our processing of their personal data, or are not satisfied with our handling of any request made by themselves in relation to their rights, also have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner's Office at <https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/> ** **

**THE ROALD DAHL MUSEUM AND STORY CENTRE – RECRUITMENT PRIVACY NOTICE**

**The kind of information about you that we collect store and use**

As someone who is applying to work with THE ROALD DAHL MUSEUM AND STORY CENTRE , we do need to collect and use information about you as an individual. We may typically collect, store and use the following types of personal information about our job candidates:

  * The information you provide on our THE ROALD DAHL MUSEUM AND STORY CENTRE  application form: name, title, addresses, telephone numbers and personal email addresses, qualifications and educational establishments attended, your employment history
  * Any additional information you provide in a CV and covering letter
  * Any information (opinion) we collect through the interview process
  * Any information (opinion) we collect following interviews, from taking up references.
  * If you are offered the job, we may collect, store and use sensitive personal information about you during the later stages of a recruitment process, including information about your health (including health and sickness records), in order to be certain that we can accommodate any specific needs you may have. ** **

**How is your personal information collected?**

We collect personal information about job candidates through the application and recruitment process, either directly from you as a candidate, or sometimes from an employment agency. 

We may sometimes collect additional information from third parties including former employers e.g. as referees. This will usually only be the case for candidates on the verge of being offered a job, subject to references. 

**How we will use information about you**

We will only use your personal information in a lawful way. The lawful basis for using personal information about job candidates is that it is in our legitimate interests to:

  * Assess your suitability for a role
  * Keep you informed about the recruitment process 
  * Keep records about our recruitment process to support the consistency and quality of our own procedures

If we collect, store and use more sensitive personal information we need to have an even stronger basis for doing so. Typically, this would require at least one of the following to be in place first:

  * Your explicit written consent 
  * A situation where we need to carry out our legal obligations or exercise rights in connection with employment 
  * A situation where it is needed in the public interest, such as for equal opportunities monitoring 
  * Where you have already made the information public
  * We do not use automated data processing in relation to job candidates ** **

**Sharing personal data**

As part of our security measures, access to personal information held by the Museum will be limited to those members of Museum staff or volunteers who have a direct role in using the data. 

We will only share the personal data we hold about you with third parties such as a recruitment agency, if that is how we received your application. We will only share the personal data we hold about you with third parties when there is a lawful reason to do so, it is in line with the specified purposes for that data, and the third party has appropriate security measures in place. 

**Storing personal data**

Your personal data will only be kept for six months after we have told you whether you have been appointed to the job. 

We keep your personal information for that period so that we can show, in the event of a legal claim, that we have not discriminated against candidates and that we have conducted the recruitment exercise in a fair and transparent way. After this period, we will securely destroy your personal information in accordance with our Data Management and Retention Schedule. 

**Your rights in relation to your personal information**

By law you have certain rights in relation to your own personal information:

  * The right to be informed about whether and how we may be processing your personal data
  * The right of access to your own personal data
  * The right to rectification if the information we have is inaccurate
  * The right to erasure if there is no longer a lawful reason for us to retain the data e.g. if consent was the lawful reason, and consent is withdrawn. This is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’ 
  * The right to restrict processing e.g. if the accuracy of your data is being challenged, you can request your data is not processed until that situation is resolved 
  * The right to data portability, when data has been provided in an easily transferable machine-readable format 
  * The right to object to the processing of your personal data at all, especially in relation to direct marketing 
  * Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling.

If you want to exercise any of these rights, or if you have any questions about this privacy notice or how we handle your personal information, please contact:

The Museum Director  
The Roald Dahl Museum and Story Centre 81-83 High Street  
Great Missenden  
HP19 0AL  
hello@roalddahlmuseum.org  
01494 892 192

**ROALD DAHL’S MARVELLOUS CHILDREN’S CHARITY – RECRUITMENT PRIVACY NOTICE**

**What will we do with your information?**

The information that applicants provide during the recruitment and selection process will only be used for the purpose of progressing their application, or to fulfil legal or regulatory requirements if necessary. The information provided will be held securely by us in an electronic and/or physical format.

ROALD DAHL’S MARVELLOUS CHILDREN’S CHARITY  will not share any of the information provided during the recruitment process with any third parties for marketing purposes or store any of your information outside of the United Kingdom or the European Union.

We will use the contact details provided to us to contact applicants in order to progress their application. We will use the other information provided to assess their suitability for the role that they have applied for. 

**What information do we ask for, and why?**

The information that we ask for (whether from the applicant or from the applicant’s referees) is used to assess the applicant’s suitability for employment and progress their application. We do not collect more information than we need to fulfil our stated purposes and will retain it for the period of time set out below.

Applicants don’t have to provide what we ask for - however it may affect their application if they don’t.

**Application Stage**

At the application stage we ask applicants for the following details:

  * Their name
  * Their address
  * Their phone number
  * Their email address
  * Details of their previous experience, including education, work history, referees and answers to questions in relation to the role that they have applied for 

We may request for the above details to be provided to us in the form of a CV, cover letter, or examples of their work. Our HR team and applicable recruiting team members will have access to all of this information.

Applicants may be asked to provide equal opportunities information. This information is not mandatory and if applicants choose not to provide it, it will not affect their application. This information will not be made available to any staff outside of our HR team in a way which can identify the applicant. Any information that is provided will be used only to produce and monitor equal opportunities statistics. 

**Selection Stage**

Our applicable recruiting team members shortlist applications for interview in conjunction with the HR team.

We may ask the applicant to take part in a telephone screening call, attend an interview and/or complete tests – or a combination of these. Information will be generated by the applicant and by us. As an example, the applicant might complete a written test, or we might take interview notes. This information is held by us.

**How long is the information retained for?**

If an applicant is unsuccessful at any stage of the process, the information provided until that point will be retained for 6 months.

Information from successful applicants will be retained in accordance with our internal Personnel Information and Data Protection policy.

Any queries about how ROALD DAHL’S MARVELLOUS CHILDREN’S CHARITY  handles applicant information should be made to: 

Data Protection Officer  
Roald Dahl’s Marvellous Children’s Charity  
Montague House   
23 Woodside Road   
Amersham   
HP6 6AA

Applicants who have any concerns regarding our processing of their personal data, or are not satisfied with our handling of any request made by themselves in relation to their rights, also have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner's Office at <https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/>
